Guide to the Steven B. Smith "Photographs of the Suburban West" Exhibit Prints, 1995-2005 RL.11196
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Steven B. Smith "Photographs of the suburban West" exhibit prints
1995-2005
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Smith, Steven B.
Duke University. Center for Documentary Studies
Archive of Documentary Arts (Duke University)
RL.11196
3 Linear Feet 2 boxes, 1 CD-ROM, 26 prints
Collection contains twenty-six 16x20 inch black-and-white matted digital prints used in Smith's book, THE WEATHER AND A PLACE TO LIVE: PHOTOGRAPHS OF THE SUBURBAN WEST, published by Duke University Press (2005). Subjects include tract housing in the West, construction sites, and other suburban landscapes that convey the impact of humans on the Western environment. His work received the First Book Prize for Photography by the Honickman Foundation and the Center for Documentary Studies at Duke University. Collection also includes CD of artist talk given by Steven Smith at the 2005 exhibit opening, "Steven Smith: Photographs of the Suburban West." Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.
27 prints; 1 CD-ROM
Collection Overview
Collection contains twenty-six 16x20 inch matted black-and-white digital prints exhibited at Duke University and used in Smith's book, THE WEATHER AND A PLACE TO LIVE: PHOTOGRAPHS OF THE SUBURBAN WEST, published by Duke University Press (2005). Subjects include tract housing in the West, construction sites, and other suburban landscapes that convey the impact of humans on the Western environment. His work received the First Book Prize for Photography by the Honickman Foundation and the Center for Documentary Studies at Duke University. Collection also includes CD of artist talk given by Steven Smith at the 2005 exhibit opening, "Steven Smith: Photographs of the Suburban West." Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.
Arrangement
Prints are arranged in original order as received.
Biographical / Historical
Steven B. Smith is a photographer whose work chronicles the transition of the Western landscape into suburbia. For this work he was awarded the 2004 First Book Prize for Photography by the Honickman Foundation and the Center for Documentary Studies at Duke University. His book, The Weather and a Place to Live: Photographs of the Suburban West, was published by Duke University Press in 2005. He has received numerous grand and awards, including Guggenheim, Kittredge and RISCA fellowships. His work has been widely exhibited and can be found in many public collections, such as the Museum of Modern Art and the Metropolitan Museum of Art. Smith received a BFA from Utah State University and an MFA from Yale. He is a professor of photography at the Rhode Island School of Design. In 2015, his second monograph, Waiting out the Latter Days, was published by TIS Press. [Source: Steven B. Smith website]
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research. Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection. All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use. Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Electronic files have been migrated to a library server and digital use copies must be requested through the collection guide and accessed in our reading room. Contact Research Services with questions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Steven B. Smith "Photographs of the suburban West" exhibit prints were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2005.
California -- Pictorial works; Colorado -- Pictorial works; Documentary photography -- West (U.S.); Housing construction -- West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works; Nature -- effect of human beings on; Nevada -- Pictorial works; Suburban homes -- West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works; Suburban homes in art; West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works; Utah -- Pictorial works; Black-and-white photographs; CD-ROMs; Digital prints; Documentary photography -- United States -- Exhibitions; Smith, Steven B.; Duke University. Center for Documentary Studies; Archive of Documentary Arts (Duke University)
- Landfill, Malibu, California, 1995 (Box 1, Image 1)
- Washington, Utah, 1997 (Box 1, Image 2)
- Castaic, California, 2001 (Box 1, Image 3)
- Caltaic, California, 2000 (Box 1, Image 4)
- North Ogden, Utah, 1999 (Box 1, Image 5)
- Draper, Utah, 2004 (Box 1, Image 6)
- Interstate 15, Lonely Peak, Sandy, Utah, 2000 (Box 1, Image 7)
- La Mirada, California, 2003 (Box 1, Image 8)
- Santa Clarita, California, 2000 (Box 1, Image 9)
- Louisville, Colorado, 2000 (Box 1, Image 10)
- Santa Clarita, California, 2000 (Box 1, Image 11)
- Bloomington, Utah, 2000 (Box 1, Image 12)
- St. George, Utah, 2003 (Box 1, Image 13)
- View lots, Valencia, California, 2001 (Box 2, Image 14)
- Las Vegas, Nevada, 1996 (Box 2, Image 15)
- St. George, Utah, 1997 (Box 2, Image 16)
- Home sites, Las Vegas, Nevada, 1996 (Box 2, Image 17)
- Las Vegas, Nevada, 1996 (Box 2, Image 18)
- Rental fence, Rancho Santa Margarita, California, 1995 (Box 2, Image 19)
- Billboard, Las Vegas, Nevada, 1996 (Box 2, Image 20)
- Mapleton, Utah, 1999 (Box 2, Image 21)
- Backyard, Valencia, California, 1996 (Box 2, Image 22)
- Draper, Utah, 2004 (Box 2, Image 23)
- Draper, Utah, 1997 (Box 2, Image 24)
- Surveryors' stakes, Valencia, California, 1996 (Box 2, Image 25)
- Stevenson Ranch, California, 2000 (Box 2, Image 26)
- Recording of artist's talk given at the exhibit opening "Steven Smith: Photographs of the Suburban West," on 10 November 2005 (CD-ROM) (Box 2)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Electronic files have been migrated to a library server and digital use copies must be requested through the collection guide and accessed in our reading room. Contact Research Services with questions.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  One audio files (WAV format) extracted from optical disc; approximately 0.6 gigabytes.